<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arvanitis Christos on arvchristos</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Arvanitis Christos on arvchristos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:30:27 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Realizing the power of Hugo shortcodes - Profile icons section</title><link>/post/realizing-the-power-of-hugo-shortcodes-profile-icons-section/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:30:27 +0300</pubDate><guid>/post/realizing-the-power-of-hugo-shortcodes-profile-icons-section/</guid><description>Hugo shortcodes offer a great method to modularize a website, separating content from other code. My website has some hacky code snippets for certain parts of it. I know that being sloppy from the beggining is never a good omen so I try to be as strict as possible with myself.
At the homepage, I include a simple section with fontawesome icons about my profiles in other social networks:
This is the hacky code that was used for this:</description></item><item><title>Matching /dev/hidraw* devices with physical devices</title><link>/post/matching-dev-hidraw-devices-with-physical-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:07:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>/post/matching-dev-hidraw-devices-with-physical-devices/</guid><description>During development of ContourUSB device driver (I&amp;rsquo; ve dedicated a post for this one) I had a hard time detecting the hidraw device created for the meter. I&amp;rsquo; ve been suggested to just print all available hidraw devices (pseudo files), then plug the meter and re-print hidraw devices to detect which one was just created. While this worked I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thrilled with the approach. So I created this simple following script.</description></item><item><title>Ascensia ContourUSB Python driver</title><link>/project/contourusb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/contourusb/</guid><description>Introduction I have used numerous glucose meters the last 20 years, but only lately I found interest in exporting statistics about my blood glucose levels. Most of the models provide a proprietary exporting tool that is AFAIK only for Windows. However, down to the connection interface level, all those devices use either USB or Serial connection. This fact led to the development of many libraries meant to interface and provide data export functionality for a number of devices, regardless of the underlying operating system.</description></item><item><title>VirtIO Paravirtualized cryptographic character device for QEMU-KVM</title><link>/project/virtio_paravirt_crypto_char_device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/virtio_paravirt_crypto_char_device/</guid><description>VirtIO Paravirtualized cryptographic character device for QEMU-KVM for Operating Systems Laboratory course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This exercise contains paradigm code for the implementation of a paravirtualized character device that exports the native /dev/crypto device of cryptodev to a QEMU VM.
Client-server chat over TCP/IP sockets (/no_encryption) For testing purposes, we first implement a simple chat system based on the client-server architecture, using TCP/IP UNIX sockets.</description></item><item><title>Page Numbering Addon - LibreOffice/OpenOffice</title><link>/project/page-numbering-addon-libreoffice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:51:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>/project/page-numbering-addon-libreoffice/</guid><description>Introduction This is a plugin for LibreOffice/OpenOffice developed during my time as a student developer for Google Summer of Code 2018. I still casually maintain the addon, although the time I can dedicate for such projects is getting reduced day by day. The addon is already used by a great number of users worldwide, translated in many languages (that would be many more if I had the time to standardize the whole localization process but that&amp;rsquo;s a whole different story to tell), and at the time of writing is the second most popular extension in LibreOffice Extensions, and the first most popular Writer extension.</description></item><item><title>Databases Course Project - Car rental service</title><link>/project/car_rental_service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/car_rental_service/</guid><description>Car rental service using PHP, MySQL and Javascript for Databases course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This application supports basic CRUD(Create Read Update Delete) operations for employees, vehicles, customers as well as some complex MySQL queries for statistics: 1. Vehicles per company branch. 2. Driver employees working on different branches. 3. Overall vehicle number recorded at our database.</description></item><item><title>Wireless mesh sensor network driver</title><link>/project/wireless_mesh_driver/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/wireless_mesh_driver/</guid><description>Wirlesh mesh sensor character device driver for Operating Systems Laboratory course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This exercise contains the implementation of a character device driver for a wireless network of sensors. Those sensors are connected in a mesh network and provide data to e central collecting station. Each of those sensors collects brightness, temperature as well as sensor battery voltage levels.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>Interested in working together or just chat? You can reach me out using one of the following:
&amp;#32;christos.arvanitis@cern.ch , arvchristos@protonmail.com , &amp;#32;arvchristos@gmail.com &amp;#32;LinkedIn &amp;#32;GitHub &amp;#32;GitLab &amp;#32;Facebook</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>