<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on arvchristos</title><link>/project/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on arvchristos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ascensia ContourUSB Python driver</title><link>/project/contourusb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/contourusb/</guid><description>Introduction I have used numerous glucose meters the last 20 years, but only lately I found interest in exporting statistics about my blood glucose levels. Most of the models provide a proprietary exporting tool that is AFAIK only for Windows. However, down to the connection interface level, all those devices use either USB or Serial connection. This fact led to the development of many libraries meant to interface and provide data export functionality for a number of devices, regardless of the underlying operating system.</description></item><item><title>VirtIO Paravirtualized cryptographic character device for QEMU-KVM</title><link>/project/virtio_paravirt_crypto_char_device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/virtio_paravirt_crypto_char_device/</guid><description>VirtIO Paravirtualized cryptographic character device for QEMU-KVM for Operating Systems Laboratory course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This exercise contains paradigm code for the implementation of a paravirtualized character device that exports the native /dev/crypto device of cryptodev to a QEMU VM.
Client-server chat over TCP/IP sockets (/no_encryption) For testing purposes, we first implement a simple chat system based on the client-server architecture, using TCP/IP UNIX sockets.</description></item><item><title>Page Numbering Addon - LibreOffice/OpenOffice</title><link>/project/page-numbering-addon-libreoffice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:51:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>/project/page-numbering-addon-libreoffice/</guid><description>Introduction This is a plugin for LibreOffice/OpenOffice developed during my time as a student developer for Google Summer of Code 2018. I still casually maintain the addon, although the time I can dedicate for such projects is getting reduced day by day. The addon is already used by a great number of users worldwide, translated in many languages (that would be many more if I had the time to standardize the whole localization process but that&amp;rsquo;s a whole different story to tell), and at the time of writing is the second most popular extension in LibreOffice Extensions, and the first most popular Writer extension.</description></item><item><title>Databases Course Project - Car rental service</title><link>/project/car_rental_service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/car_rental_service/</guid><description>Car rental service using PHP, MySQL and Javascript for Databases course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This application supports basic CRUD(Create Read Update Delete) operations for employees, vehicles, customers as well as some complex MySQL queries for statistics: 1. Vehicles per company branch. 2. Driver employees working on different branches. 3. Overall vehicle number recorded at our database.</description></item><item><title>Wireless mesh sensor network driver</title><link>/project/wireless_mesh_driver/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/wireless_mesh_driver/</guid><description>Wirlesh mesh sensor character device driver for Operating Systems Laboratory course of Electrical and Computer Engineering School of NTUA Athens. You can find the project code on GitHub
This exercise contains the implementation of a character device driver for a wireless network of sensors. Those sensors are connected in a mesh network and provide data to e central collecting station. Each of those sensors collects brightness, temperature as well as sensor battery voltage levels.</description></item></channel></rss>